<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Rachel Lin</title>
    <description>Rachel Lin | Designer + Developer
</description>
    <link>/</link>
    <atom:link href="/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Mon, 05 Jun 2017 22:38:46 -0700</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 05 Jun 2017 22:38:46 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.1.2</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>TripIt Alternate Flights</title>
        <description>&lt;section class=&quot;project-body&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;b&gt;*Disclaimer: The project is still in progress, so stay tuned for future updates!&lt;/b&gt; If you’d like to learn more feel free to &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:linrac@gmail.com&quot;&gt;reach out&lt;/a&gt;.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 06 May 2017 14:22:04 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>/tripit/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/tripit/</guid>
        
        
        <category>featured</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>BUILD Simplification of Controls</title>
        <description>&lt;section class=&quot;project-body&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;b&gt;*Disclaimer: Some parts of my work are still pre-release, so stay tuned for future updates! The illustrations below are not the final design, unless stated otherwise.&lt;/b&gt; 
&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;h2&gt;Problem&lt;/h2&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
  I simplified two of the most frequently used controls, which are the essential building blocks for creating apps in BUILD. 
&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;b&gt;Forms&lt;/b&gt; are difficult to edit and manipulate, given its complex, multiple-layer hierarchy. Quick, simple tasks from adding rows to adding individuals controls to a row were unintuitive and time-consuming. Forms are used to display information, input fields, and other data on pages. 
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
&lt;b&gt;Radio Buttons&lt;/b&gt; is a new control that consists of a group of radio buttons. It previously existed as an individual radio button control that lacked the functionality of selecting a radio button out of a group of radio buttons. I made a new control with expanded capabilities so that multiple radio button groups could be included in Forms. 
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;section class=&quot;project-body&quot;&gt;
  &lt;h2&gt;Role&lt;/h2&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
  &lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Led end-to-end design efforts from user research to design implementation while collaborating with Product Managers and frontend developers&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Achieved greater usability with key stakeholders&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Introduced direct manipulation on Canvas&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Improved properties panel settings and more intuitive layout formatting&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;section class=&quot;project-body&quot;&gt;
  &lt;h2&gt;Reformation of Forms&lt;/h2&gt;
  &lt;h3 class=&quot;project-body&quot;&gt;Mindset Mismatch&lt;/h3&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
  I first tested the current implementation of Forms to gain a deeper understanding of the usability issues. We discovered from usability testing that users’ mindset of creating a Form did not match what was in place. Their expectations of adding rows and elements to rows were based on their experiences of using software like Microsoft Excel and Powerpoint.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;blockquote&gt;
    I got frustrated when I was trying to add an extra row, and dragging was not being consistent
    &lt;footer&gt;Program Manager&lt;/footer&gt;
  &lt;/blockquote&gt;
  &lt;h3 class=&quot;project-body&quot;&gt;Foundational Changes&lt;/h3&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
 We explored many ideas to improve manipulation and structure of Forms while working within the technical constraints of UI5 Controls and the limitations of dragging and dropping controls on the Canvas. We first focused on developing the following concepts to be the most valuable and quickest to implement.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
  &lt;b&gt;One Form&lt;/b&gt;: The two Form Controls were Simple Form and Advanced Form. Users were confused of the differences between the two types of Forms, so we consolidated to one
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;b&gt;Form Row&lt;/b&gt;: we introduced the concept of a Form Row (comprises of a Label and another Form Control element on the right side), so that users could easily select, rearrange, duplicate, and delete rows in a Form. 
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/img/portfolio/build/FormRow.png&quot; class=&quot;img-responsive center-block&quot;&gt;
    &lt;figcaption&gt;Form Row&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
  &lt;b&gt;Show Form-specific Controls&lt;/b&gt;: When a user clicks on a Form or any element within a Form, the Controls Panel will surface controls that could be added to Forms. The user can quickly find the appropriate control to add to a Form Row. This pattern of viewing controls specific to a selected control will be applied to other controls that contain children elements.
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/img/portfolio/build/CPFormControls.png&quot; class=&quot;img-responsive center-block&quot;&gt;
    &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;b&gt;Now Live&lt;/b&gt;: Controls Panel only shows Form Controls when a Form or its children are selected&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;b&gt;Contextual Right Click Menu&lt;/b&gt;: A quick alternative to adding, duplicating, and deleting a row. There is the additional capability to add row above or below a selected row.

&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/img/portfolio/build/RightClickMenu1.png&quot; class=&quot;img-responsive center-block&quot;&gt;
    &lt;figcaption&gt;Contextual Right Click Menu for a Row and Form&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;h3 class=&quot;project-body&quot;&gt;Unexpected Challenge: Form Groups&lt;/h3&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
As we were ready to finalize designs, a new requirement was introduced for us to include Form Groups into the Forms. We revisited the drawing board to see how the extra layer of hierarchy would change the structure of our designs. After the foundational changes were finished being built in the production site, we tested participants’ ability to build a form. We provided screenshots of a Purchase Order form (a common customer use case) for participants to recreate - from a simple form to a form with additional groups.
  &lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;blockquote&gt;
    It shouldn&#39;t have taken 30 minutes to assemble this form
    &lt;footer&gt;UX Designer&lt;/footer&gt;
  &lt;/blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
  Users still struggled to create a form because the process still required too many clicks to reach the lowest level of the Form hierarchy, the most edited level. Users failed to reformat and rearrange Form Groups for more elaborate forms.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;h3 class=&quot;project-body&quot;&gt;Final Solution: Abstracting Layers&lt;/h3&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
  We solved the problem by creating handlers to directly select the lower level elements and performing direct manipulations on element-level and row level interactions on the Canvas. We also renamed “Form Groups” to Form Sections, since users were confused by the nomenclature of “Form Groups.” 
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
&lt;b&gt;Changes for Easier Manipulation:&lt;/b&gt;
  &lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;Handlers&lt;/b&gt;: select rows, drag and rearrange Form Sections&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;Add Form-Specific Controls via “+” Button on Canvas&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;Add Form Section Button: Direct manipulation on canvas&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;Layout Formatting&lt;/b&gt;: define # of columns in Form for specified device (mobile, tablet, desktop) and define arrangement of labels (side-by-side or stacked)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;section class=&quot;project-body&quot;&gt;
  &lt;h2&gt;Radio Buttons: Better Together&lt;/h2&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/img/portfolio/build/RadioButtons.png&quot; class=&quot;img-responsive center-block&quot;&gt;
  &lt;h3 class=&quot;project-body&quot;&gt;Grouping Radio Buttons &amp; Checkboxes&lt;/h3&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
  BUILD only had individual radio buttons and checkboxes that could be dragged onto the canvas from the Control Panel. I was tasked with figuring out how to best structure Radio Buttons, and how that could also apply to Checkboxes (when it came time to design the Checkboxes control).
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;h3 class=&quot;project-body&quot;&gt;Validating Multiple Choice vs. Separate Radio Buttons and Checkboxes&lt;/h3&gt;
  &lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/img/portfolio/build/radiobuttonpaperproto.jpg&quot; class=&quot;img-responsive center-block&quot;&gt;
    &lt;figcaption&gt;Testing the Multiple Choice concept with a paper prototype&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
  Because the Checkbox control is structurally similar to the Radio Button control, I wanted to validate whether to combine Radio Buttons and Checkboxes under one control named “Multiple Choice.” In the case that the user wanted to switch from Radio Buttons to Checkboxes and vice versa, the user should be able to maintain the same data or text they inputted. We quickly tested the concept with a paper prototype. During research, we discovered that the concept of “Multiple Choice” conveys different meanings, especially to non-native English speakers. 
  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  To me, “Multiple Choice” means selecting multiple options so I would expect Checkboxes to appear if I dragged the control to the Canvas
  &lt;footer&gt;Business Analyst&lt;/footer&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Based on those confusions, I decided to separate Radio Buttons and Checkboxes as two separate controls. Participants thought that providing the capability to switch between the two controls while maintaining the same data and text input was valuable.
  &lt;h3 class=&quot;project-body&quot;&gt;Shipping Changes&lt;/h3&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
  &lt;b&gt;Direct Manipulation on Canvas&lt;/b&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Adding a new radio button with “+” button&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Right click contextual menu for adding, duplicating, and deleting radio buttons&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
  &lt;b&gt;Properties Panel&lt;/b&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Formatting horizontal and vertical layout&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
  The next steps will be to figure out how to maintain data while switching between different controls.
  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;section class=&quot;project-body&quot;&gt;
  &lt;h2&gt;Lessons Learned&lt;/h2&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;b&gt;Changes Beyond One Control&lt;/b&gt;: In the process of redesigning controls, I had to be mindful of any changes made to Form or Radio Buttons and how they could affect the usability of other controls. Simplifying a control means finding opportunities to simplify other structurally similar controls.
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;b&gt;Get unstuck&lt;/b&gt; by testing early with incremental changes. Finding the right fidelity to test can save time and eliminate technical debt in the long run. For Radio Buttons, paper prototyping the multiple choice concept proved to be the best way to quickly disprove my hypothesis and determine which path to choose for my design.
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;b&gt;Document Your Progress&lt;/b&gt;: Organizing ideas from brainstorming sessions, design reviews, and meeting notes allowed me to revisit ideas that were conceived from earlier parts of the process but tossed away. They may prove to be viable solutions later down the road (highly recommend Dropbox Paper to keep track!)
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;section class=&quot;project-body&quot;&gt;
  &lt;h2&gt;Thank you&lt;/h2&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
I’m grateful for the unique challenge of designing UI controls with such a supportive, talented team. Shoutout to Suhaib Syed (Designer), Wenjing Yang (Designer), and Hong Wang (Product Manager) for leading the stride on simplifying controls and improving the overall usability of the Prototyping Tool in BUILD!
  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 06 Apr 2017 14:22:04 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>/build/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/build/</guid>
        
        
        <category>featured</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>ThredUP Personal Shops</title>
        <description>&lt;section class=&quot;project-body&quot;&gt;
  &lt;h2&gt;Problem&lt;/h2&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
  Only a very small percentage of users onboarded to the feature (not allowed to disclose figures), yet its users have the highest average order values.
  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;section class=&quot;project-body&quot;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Role&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Led a strategic redesign by analyzing data and conducting interviews that led to key findings influencing user flows and KPIs set.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Worked closely with Product, Engineering, Design, and Marketing in the process of developing specs and receiving feedback&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Created prototypes in FramerJS and facilitated user testing sessions that influenced rollout to another platform.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;
&lt;section class=&quot;project-body&quot;&gt;
  &lt;h2&gt;Defining the Product Strategy&lt;/h2&gt;
  &lt;h3 class=&quot;project-body&quot;&gt;Identifying Existing Successful Trends&lt;/h3&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
      I first pulled current data on users with Personal Shops to find the top used search filters and looked at which platforms (web, mobile/web, iOS, and Android) were the most popular and had the highest average order values.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;h3 class=&quot;project-body&quot;&gt;An In-Depth Understanding of Users&lt;/h3&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
     I surveyed users with over 10 Personal Shops to understand their behaviors for saving so many shops in the first place. I followed up with 7 users who consented to following up with me for a more in-depth discussion about their use of thredUP and other shopping apps.
  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Based on my phone interviews with the users, I created a mental model to understand the user&#39;s train of thought.
    &lt;h3 class=&quot;project-body&quot;&gt;Mental Model&lt;/h3&gt;
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Can I quickly find relevant items?&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;How can I find great deals that caters to my family&#39;s lifestyle?&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;How can I easily shop my favorite brands?&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Will these items fit me?&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Will it save me search time?&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;How can we get coveted items first?&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;

&lt;section class=&quot;project-body&quot;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Style Profile&lt;/h2&gt;
We also further refined the idea of creating a Style Profile for every account in order to &lt;strong&gt;set Sizes and top 10 brands&lt;/strong&gt;, based on the findings of a high percentage of users caring about their the brands they purchase and wanting to discover more items to similar brands.
&lt;/section&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;section class=&quot;project-body&quot;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Iteration&lt;/h2&gt;
  &lt;h3 class=&quot;project-body&quot;&gt;Validating Ideas&lt;/h3&gt;
The aim of the first iteration (prototyped in FramerJS) was to validate and answer:
&lt;li&gt;Would customers be interested in seeing recent searches, suggested searches, and popular searches?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Does saving the search into a separate tab (&quot;Pocket&quot;) increase engagement?&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;div id=&quot;myCarousel&quot; class=&quot;carousel slide&quot; data-ride=&quot;carousel&quot;&gt;
  &lt;!-- Carousel indicators --&gt;
  &lt;!-- Wrapper for carousel items --&gt;
  &lt;div class=&quot;carousel-inner&quot;&gt;
      &lt;div class=&quot;item active&quot;&gt;
          &lt;img src=&quot;/img/portfolio/thredup-ps/v1-home.png&quot; alt=&quot;First Slide&quot; /&gt;
          &lt;div class=&quot;carousel-caption active&quot;&gt;
          The Feed is the main home screen that includes a personal greeting, Recent Searches, Suggested, and Popular. The color coding for each search was based on shop-type (Women, Girls, Boys).
          &lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;div class=&quot;item&quot;&gt;
          &lt;img src=&quot;/img/portfolio/thredup-ps/v1-popup.png&quot; alt=&quot;Second Slide&quot; /&gt;
          &lt;div class=&quot;carousel-caption active&quot;&gt;
          Notify the user about saving a search to Pocket, where all of the saved searches are stored
          &lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;div class=&quot;item&quot;&gt;
          &lt;img src=&quot;/img/portfolio/thredup-ps/v1-pocket.png&quot; alt=&quot;Third Slide&quot; /&gt;
          &lt;div class=&quot;carousel-caption active&quot;&gt;
          Inside Pocket: The red circle notifies how many new arrivals there are in the saved search.
          &lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;div class=&quot;item&quot;&gt;
          &lt;img src=&quot;/img/portfolio/thredup-ps/v1-pocketedit.png&quot; alt=&quot;Third Slide&quot; /&gt;
          &lt;div class=&quot;carousel-caption active&quot;&gt;
          In the past, users were unable to update their saved search directly and we also wanted to provide notification settings to set frequency of notifications for new arrivals. The pink copy incentivizes users to save shops in order receive a discount.
          &lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;div class=&quot;item&quot;&gt;
          &lt;img src=&quot;/img/portfolio/thredup-ps/v1-PLP.png&quot; alt=&quot;Third Slide&quot; /&gt;
          &lt;div class=&quot;carousel-caption active&quot;&gt;
          The Product Listing Page (PLP) for the saved search shows the saved search bar, so users are clear of which shop they are browsing.
          &lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;ol class=&quot;carousel-indicators&quot;&gt;
      &lt;li data-target=&quot;#myCarousel&quot; data-slide-to=&quot;0&quot; class=&quot;active&quot;&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li data-target=&quot;#myCarousel&quot; data-slide-to=&quot;1&quot;&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li data-target=&quot;#myCarousel&quot; data-slide-to=&quot;2&quot;&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li data-target=&quot;#myCarousel&quot; data-slide-to=&quot;3&quot;&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li data-target=&quot;#myCarousel&quot; data-slide-to=&quot;4&quot;&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ol&gt;   
  &lt;!-- Carousel controls --&gt;
  &lt;a class=&quot;carousel-control left&quot; href=&quot;#myCarousel&quot; data-slide=&quot;prev&quot;&gt;
      &lt;span class=&quot;glyphicon glyphicon-chevron-left&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;a class=&quot;carousel-control right&quot; href=&quot;#myCarousel&quot; data-slide=&quot;next&quot;&gt;
      &lt;span class=&quot;glyphicon glyphicon-chevron-right&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;cta&quot;&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;http://share.framerjs.com/y2r6k8czd5k7/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;button class=&quot;cta&quot;&gt;View Prototype&lt;/button&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
After conducting the first user testing session on-site with 6 users who had at least one Personal Shop, I gained a lot of helpful insights for improving the next iteration.
&lt;h3 class=&quot;project-body&quot;&gt;Findings&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Simplify the view - remove color coding.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The concept of &quot;Pocket&quot; was too confusing.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Users wanted to be able to click through a feed row to see the PLP.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Users are not interested in seeing popular saved searches.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 class=&quot;project-body&quot;&gt;Refining the Design&lt;/h3&gt;
  Since I had limited time to conduct another user test, I tested this prototype internally with select employees from Product, Engineering, Design, and Marketing to gather feedback from multiple points of view. I updated my FramerJS prototype based on findings from usability testing for version 1.0.
  &lt;p&gt;
    &lt;div id=&quot;v2Carousel&quot; class=&quot;carousel slide&quot; data-ride=&quot;carousel&quot;&gt;
    &lt;!-- Carousel indicators --&gt;
    &lt;!-- Wrapper for carousel items --&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;carousel-inner&quot;&gt;
        &lt;div class=&quot;item active&quot;&gt;
            &lt;img src=&quot;/img/portfolio/thredup-ps/v2-home.png&quot; class=&quot;img-responsive&quot; alt=&quot;First Slide&quot; /&gt;
            &lt;div class=&quot;carousel-caption active&quot;&gt;
            &quot;My Shop&quot; only displays rows of recently searches. Users can save shops by tapping the heart.
            &lt;/div&gt;
        &lt;/div&gt;
        &lt;div class=&quot;item&quot;&gt;
            &lt;img src=&quot;/img/portfolio/thredup-ps/v2-edit.png&quot; alt=&quot;Second Slide&quot; /&gt;
            &lt;div class=&quot;carousel-caption active&quot;&gt;
            The user can easily edit, delete, and modify notification settings for the saved search.
            &lt;/div&gt;
        &lt;/div&gt;
        &lt;div class=&quot;item&quot;&gt;
            &lt;img src=&quot;/img/portfolio/thredup-ps/v2-PLPsave.png&quot; alt=&quot;Third Slide&quot; /&gt;
            &lt;div class=&quot;carousel-caption active&quot;&gt;
           Save Search bottom bar button is a clear call-to-action.
            &lt;/div&gt;
        &lt;/div&gt;
        &lt;div class=&quot;item&quot;&gt;
            &lt;img src=&quot;/img/portfolio/thredup-ps/v2-promo.png&quot; alt=&quot;Fourth Slide&quot; /&gt;
            &lt;div class=&quot;carousel-caption active&quot;&gt;
            Reward users for saving 3 shops by offering a promo.
            &lt;/div&gt;
        &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;ol class=&quot;carousel-indicators&quot;&gt;
        &lt;li data-target=&quot;#v2Carousel&quot; data-slide-to=&quot;0&quot; class=&quot;active&quot;&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;li data-target=&quot;#v2Carousel&quot; data-slide-to=&quot;1&quot;&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;li data-target=&quot;#v2Carousel&quot; data-slide-to=&quot;2&quot;&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;li data-target=&quot;#v2Carousel&quot; data-slide-to=&quot;3&quot;&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ol&gt;   
    &lt;!-- Carousel controls --&gt;
    &lt;a class=&quot;carousel-control left&quot; href=&quot;#v2Carousel&quot; data-slide=&quot;prev&quot;&gt;
        &lt;span class=&quot;glyphicon glyphicon-chevron-left&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;a class=&quot;carousel-control right&quot; href=&quot;#v2Carousel&quot; data-slide=&quot;next&quot;&gt;
        &lt;span class=&quot;glyphicon glyphicon-chevron-right&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;cta&quot;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;http://share.framerjs.com/daab0qd1fmzh/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;button class=&quot;cta&quot;&gt;View Prototype&lt;/button&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;br /&gt;
  &lt;br /&gt;
  &lt;h3 class=&quot;project-body&quot;&gt;Findings&lt;/h3&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;We should rolllout to web, instead of mobile first.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;There were mixed reactions to the heart iconography&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;section class=&quot;project-body&quot;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Execution&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 class=&quot;project-body&quot;&gt;Challenges&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;It was tempting to include many new features for the redesign of Personal Shops, but I learned to &lt;strong&gt;prioritize features&lt;/strong&gt; and make tradeoffs given the scope of the project. This simplification allowed for a more simplified design that was easy on the eyes.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I discovered the technical limitations for mobile after speaking with the Engineering team, so I had to quickly find an alternative solution for web.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 class=&quot;project-body&quot;&gt;Takeaways&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Involve other stakeholders earlier in the process to learn about potential contraints.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Simplicity and elegance rules. Think about information hierarchy when considering the visual. Only emphasize what needs to be emphasized. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;




&lt;!-- 
&lt;figure class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-ruby&quot; data-lang=&quot;ruby&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;def&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nf&quot;&gt;print_hi&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;name&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;puts&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;Hi, &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;si&quot;&gt;#{&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;name&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;si&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;end&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;print_hi&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;&#39;Tom&#39;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;c1&quot;&gt;#=&amp;gt; prints &#39;Hi, Tom&#39; to STDOUT.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;


Check out the [Jekyll docs][jekyll-docs] for more info on how to get the most out of Jekyll. File all bugs/feature requests at [Jekyll’s GitHub repo][jekyll-gh]. If you have questions, you can ask them on [Jekyll Talk][jekyll-talk].

[jekyll-docs]: http://jekyllrb.com/docs/home
[jekyll-gh]:   https://github.com/jekyll/jekyll
[jekyll-talk]: https://talk.jekyllrb.com/ --&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/section&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jun 2016 14:22:04 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>/thredup-ps/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/thredup-ps/</guid>
        
        
        <category>archive</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>SmartBrush</title>
        <description>&lt;section class=&quot;project-body&quot;&gt;
  &lt;h2&gt;Problem&lt;/h2&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
      Children who learn poor brushing and flossing techniques from their parents often carry these habits into their adulthood. Neglecting dental hygiene can lead to unwanted cavities and gum diseases down the road, which can hurt self-confidence in one&#39;s appearance.
  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;section class=&quot;project-body&quot;&gt;
  &lt;h2&gt;Role&lt;/h2&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Project Manager and Lead Designer&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Ensured team of engineers met deadlines and contributed to design process&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Designed visual assets, animations and overall UX Design&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Sketched concepts, developed user journey map and intereviewed users&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Implemented GifViews in Android&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;section class=&quot;project-body&quot;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;SmartBrush in Action&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;video-module responsive-video&quot;&gt;
&lt;iframe width=&quot;650&quot; height=&quot;400&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/7vfUYkNVRzE&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;section class=&quot;project-body&quot;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Defining the Strategy&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 class=&quot;project-body&quot;&gt;Brainstorming&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We wanted most of the interactions during brushing to occur when using the watch. After weighing the constraints, pros, and cons of our top three ideas, we selected a dental hygiene app. We thought it held the most potential for designing unique interactions for the watch interface in particular. There were many more ideas that we could implement for solving the problem of poor dental hygiene through gamification, providing facts, and keeping track of progress through a numerical system.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 class=&quot;project-body&quot;&gt;Ideation &amp;amp; Sketches&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After discovering the saturation of dental hygiene apps for children in the Play Store and recognizing there is still a need for teens and young adults to correct their poor brushing and flossing habits, we decided to pivot to target 10-20 year olds. 
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 class=&quot;project-body&quot;&gt;User Journey Map&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.figma.com/file/Laa1xLrzw4I487dMAVAU743E/Smart-Brush-User-Journey-Map&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/portfolio/smartbrush/UserJourneyMap.png&quot; class=&quot;img-responsive&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 class=&quot;project-body&quot;&gt;Sketches&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.figma.com/file/guugKmS6m1uQWVMW6KBj6D/CS-160-Nurse-Joy-and-the-ChancPaper-Sketches-Public&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/portfolio/smartbrush/sketch.png&quot; class=&quot;img-responsive&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
We based our sketches on the User Journey Map.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;section class=&quot;project-body&quot;&gt;
  &lt;h2&gt;Initial Research&lt;/h2&gt;
  &lt;h3 class=&quot;project-body&quot;&gt;Competitive Analysis&lt;/h3&gt;
  &lt;strong&gt;Top 3 Competitors:&lt;/strong&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Chomper Chums&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Quickbrush&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Aquafresh Brush Time&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
  With the plethora of dental hygiene apps for children, we wanted to differentiate and focus on designing an app for a slightly older user base of young teens to young adults.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;h3 class=&quot;project-body&quot;&gt;User Interviews&lt;/h3&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
  Our initial interviews with a &lt;strong&gt;dental assistant, mother of two children, and a teenage student&lt;/strong&gt; allowed us to dive deeper into identifying the user&#39;s top needs and primary tasks for our app. The dental assistant emphasized the importance of &lt;strong&gt;flossing&lt;/strong&gt; and finding ways to &lt;strong&gt;entertain children&lt;/strong&gt; so that they would be motivated to brush their teeth. The mother shared with us how influential parents are for teaching their children about dental hygiene. The teenage student revealed his dental hygiene habits and how it is tied with his &lt;strong&gt;self-esteem in regards to physical appearance&lt;/strong&gt;. He also suggested an aspect of &lt;strong&gt;gamification&lt;/strong&gt; to make the experience of brushing teeth and flossing more enjoyable. We took all of these findings into account in our process of building features.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;h3 class=&quot;project-body&quot;&gt;Top 5 User Needs&lt;/h3&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Have a fun and entertaining experience so brushing teeth won’t feel like a hassle.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Receiving feedback and tracking progress for techniques.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Learn proper brushing habits and techniques.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Not slowing down the brushing/flossing process.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Motivation to maintain good oral health and prevent dental disorders.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;section class=&quot;project-body&quot;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Iteration&lt;/h2&gt;
  &lt;h3 class=&quot;project-body&quot;&gt;Wireframing&lt;/h3&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
  Our team used &lt;a href=&quot;http://figma.com&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Figma&lt;/a&gt; as our primary collaborative, prototyping tool (includes a handy Slack integration). We wanted our first wireframe to accomplish the three primary tasks.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;h3 class=&quot;project-body&quot;&gt;3 Primary Tasks&lt;/h3&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Brushing&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Flossing&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Checking Progress and Rankings&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;h3 class=&quot;project-body&quot;&gt;Version 1.0&lt;/h3&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/img/portfolio/smartbrush/wireframev1.png&quot; class=&quot;img-responsive&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
  &lt;div class=&quot;cta&quot;&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.figma.com/file/GJd7n0GcPV36Rmo6Tg14Un/Final-Wireframes-v1-Public&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
      &lt;button class=&quot;cta&quot;&gt;View Wireframe&lt;/button&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
 &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
 &lt;h3 class=&quot;project-body&quot;&gt;Version 2.0&lt;/h3&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/img/portfolio/smartbrush/wireframev2.png&quot; class=&quot;img-responsive&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
  &lt;div class=&quot;cta&quot;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.figma.com/file/5036UJPwm5jX8cpyTlir3k/PROG-03-Milestone-1-Public&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    &lt;button class=&quot;cta&quot;&gt;View Wireframe&lt;/button&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
  After receiving feedback from TAs, usability testing participants, and fellow students, here are the key changes made for the second version:
  &lt;p&gt;
  &lt;table class=&quot;table table-bordered&quot;&gt;
  &lt;tr&gt;
  	&lt;th&gt;Watch&lt;/th&gt;
  	&lt;th&gt;Phone&lt;/th&gt;
  &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;tr&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Simplify the view of the Home Screen: remove logo text and recreate circular buttons in order to avoid the fat finger problem.&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Remove the Home Screen as a summary, but instead have the users toggle between two tabs to view My Activity and Rankings.&lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;tr&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Changed from 6 brush screens (15 seconds each) to 4 brush screens (30 seconds each) - as recommended by the dental assistant.&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Only keeps track of current streak and longest streak. The overall health score was unclear to the users.&lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Results Screen includes the latest streak count.&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
  
&lt;/table&gt;	
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/img/portfolio/smartbrush/branding.png&quot; class=&quot;img-responsive&quot; /&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;section class=&quot;project-body&quot;&gt;
  &lt;h2&gt;Final Prototype&lt;/h2&gt;
  We developed the final prototype on Android. Brushing animations (made in After Effects) indicate the progress of brushing your teeth as the teeth turn from yellow to white and the pulsating effect highlight the areas of your teeth to brush. We established a streak system in which a streak is equal to brushing twice in a day and flossing once during the day. The counter resets daily at midnight. After the 15-second timer for the Brushing Screens reaches 0, the watch will vibrate to indicate an automatic transition to the next screen.
  &lt;p&gt;
  &lt;h3 class=&quot;project-body&quot;&gt;Final Flow&lt;/h3&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;/img/portfolio/smartbrush/finaldesignflow.png&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/portfolio/smartbrush/finaldesignflow.png&quot; class=&quot;img-responsive&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
  &lt;h3 class=&quot;project-body&quot;&gt;Animations&lt;/h3&gt;
  &lt;div class=&quot;row&quot;&gt;
  &lt;div class=&quot;col-xs-5 center-block&quot;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/img/portfolio/smartbrush/bottomrightdiagram.gif&quot; class=&quot;img-responsive&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;div class=&quot;col-xs-5 center-block&quot;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/img/portfolio/smartbrush/flossing.gif&quot; class=&quot;img-responsive&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;section class=&quot;project-body&quot;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Execution&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 class=&quot;project-body&quot;&gt;Technical Challenges&lt;/h3&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Running the Gif Views&lt;/strong&gt;: our flossing animation was unable to play on physical watch because it ran out of memory, but it played normally on the emulator.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Storing and updating the streak count on the phone and watch after brushing&lt;/strong&gt;: We needed to figure out a system of updating the streaks. We set a timestamp at midnight to reset the count of brushing and flossing. The data for streak counts are stored on the phone, but the watch retries this information to update the streak count and send the data back to the phone.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;section class=&quot;project-body&quot;&gt;
  &lt;h2&gt;Takeaways&lt;/h2&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
  Overall, I had a wonderful experience of learning how to develop an app in Android with a team and learning about the UI guidelines for Android and Android Wear. This is also the first project where I designed an experience and programmed for wearables.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  Here are the valuable lessons I learned along the way:
  &lt;li&gt;Know the &lt;a href=&quot;http://developer.android.com/design/wear/patterns.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Android Wear UI Patterns&lt;/a&gt; front and back before diving into sketching, wireframing, and creating visual design elements.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Technical constraints, such as the physical handware running out of memory for playing animations, can influence the final design implementation and may require an alternative solution.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;section class=&quot;project-body&quot;&gt;
   &lt;h2&gt;Credit&lt;/h2&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Contextual Inquiries: Rachel Lin, Nithish Arunkumar, Mukund Chillikanti&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Visual Design, Animations, and UI Design: Rachel Lin&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Backend (Android): Mukund Chillikanti&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Rankings Screen (Android): Nithish Arunkumar&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;My Activity Screen (Android): Tait Gu&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Gif Views (Android): Rachel Lin&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/section&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/section&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 06 May 2016 14:22:04 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>/smartbrush/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/smartbrush/</guid>
        
        
        <category>archive</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>TrashScan</title>
        <description>&lt;section class=&quot;project-body&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
TrashScan is a revolutionary new way of waste management and sorting. With it, we can more easily sort trash into the correct bins: compost, bottles &amp; cans, mixed paper, and landfill. Simply place your trash on top of the platform and TrashScan will let you know which bin to place it in. This technology not only makes it easier to sort trash, but it works towards educating users on the intricacies of recycling and composting in order help communities achieve zero waste by 2020. I&#39;ve only included the highlights of the project here, but a more comprehensive write-up can be found on &lt;a href=&quot;&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Hackster&lt;/a&gt;. 
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
TrashScan has been featured as a &lt;a href=&quot;http://jacobsinstitute.berkeley.edu/student-project/trashscan/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Project Spotlight&lt;/a&gt; for the &lt;a href=&quot;http://jacobsinstitute.berkeley.edu&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Jacobs Institute for Design Innovation&lt;/a&gt;. Our team also had the honor of presenting our prototype to the Jacobs Institute Advisory Board.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;section class=&quot;project-body&quot;&gt;
  		&lt;h2&gt;Problem&lt;/h2&gt;
  		  Students do not know what bin their trash belongs in. People don&#39;t care about what bin their trash belongs in. Cross-contamination in bins prevents composting.
&lt;/section&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;section class=&quot;project-body&quot;&gt;
  	&lt;h2&gt;Role&lt;/h2&gt;
  		  &lt;li&gt;Project manager&lt;/li&gt;	
	      &lt;li&gt;Conducted ethnographic interviews and regularly met with interviewees&lt;/li&gt;
	      &lt;li&gt;Created the animations in Processing&lt;/li&gt;
	      &lt;li&gt;Sketched concepts and developed user&#39;s interaction with the platform&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;/section&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;section class=&quot;project-body&quot;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Initial Research&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
We interviewed Monica and Nicole, two students coordinators from Cal Recycling. From our first interview with Monica, we learned about the inefficiencies of sorting trash during waste audits. These issues originate from human errors of cross-contamination between bins. It is difficult to teach 40,000 students to correct their habits and take the time to learn about disposing in the correct bin. 
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
In a follow up interview, we learned that many of the common errors were:
	&lt;li&gt;dry paper should go in mixed paper (no soiled/wet paper)&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;plastics were found in compost, but they don’t belong in the compost bin (should go to landfill or bottles &amp; cans)&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;The non-compostable spoons from off campus were placed in compost&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;section class=&quot;project-body&quot;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Design Process&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Our first design included a box with lights positioned at the top. A camera would look into the box, and once the item was sorted, a light would indicate the correct bin. However, this initial design was too constricting and bulky, so we simplified out design to a flat platform. The user would place their trash onto the platform and a light attached to the right side of the platform would light up, much like the initial design. In our third design, we wanted to be able to add more to the device and have some sort of imagery to be displayed on the platform. Thus, we added in a projector next to the camera and removed the lights. The device would have a flat platform on which an image would be displayed. We would customize the image per bin. 
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
For our final design, we used a monitor, which conveniently served both as the platform, as well as where the visuals and sound played from. We place this monitor inside a box.  Users would see an initial start screen, with simple instructions guiding them on how to use TrashScan.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;section class=&quot;project-body&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;row&quot;&gt;
	&lt;div class=&quot;col-md-4&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/portfolio/trashscan/iteration1.png&quot; class=&quot;img-responsive center-block&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
	&lt;div class=&quot;col-md-4&quot;&gt;
		&lt;img src=&quot;/img/portfolio/trashscan/iteration2.png&quot; class=&quot;img-responsive center-block&quot;&gt;
	&lt;/div&gt;
	&lt;div class=&quot;col-md-4&quot;&gt;
		&lt;img src=&quot;/img/portfolio/trashscan/iteration3.png&quot; class=&quot;img-responsive center-block&quot;&gt;
	&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Because signage is often hidden and ineffective for telling people what belongs in each bin, we wanted to display animations and play sounds to engage the user and associate each bin with a sound and graphic. We included facts stated during the interviews as part of the messaging. For compost, we played a victorious sound to encourage composting, and an error “wah-wah” noise to discourage people from using the landfill.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;section class=&quot;project-body&quot;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Final Prototype&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;video-module responsive-video&quot;&gt;
&lt;iframe width=&quot;655&quot; height=&quot;375&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/xkhOMdKdvc4&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
We made animations with &lt;a href=&quot;http://py.processing.org/&quot;&gt;Processing.py&lt;/a&gt;, then converted it to video so it could be played on Raspberry Pi. After an object is identified and sorted into its corresponding bin, the monitor will play the animation for its bin. We included sound to help the user remember which bin the object belongs to. For the &lt;strong&gt;Compost&lt;/strong&gt; bin, we play a victorious sound to encourage composting; for &lt;strong&gt;Landfill&lt;/strong&gt; we play a sad sound to discourage putting waste in the landfill. Fun facts on the screen encourages education as part of the user&#39;s interaction with the platform.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 class=&quot;project-body&quot;&gt;Greeting Screen&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;iframe src=&quot;https://player.vimeo.com/video/166338989&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;480&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; webkitallowfullscreen mozallowfullscreen allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;h3 class=&quot;project-body&quot;&gt;Compost Sort&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;iframe src=&quot;https://player.vimeo.com/video/168866419&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;480&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; webkitallowfullscreen mozallowfullscreen allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;h3 class=&quot;project-body&quot;&gt;Bottles &amp; Cans Sort&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;iframe src=&quot;https://player.vimeo.com/video/168866418&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;480&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; webkitallowfullscreen mozallowfullscreen allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;h3 class=&quot;project-body&quot;&gt;Mixed Paper Sort&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;iframe src=&quot;https://player.vimeo.com/video/168866582&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;480&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; webkitallowfullscreen mozallowfullscreen allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;h3 class=&quot;project-body&quot;&gt;Landfill Sort&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;iframe src=&quot;https://player.vimeo.com/video/168866581&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;480&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; webkitallowfullscreen mozallowfullscreen allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;section class=&quot;project-body&quot;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Final Thoughts&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 class=&quot;project-body&quot;&gt;Challenges&lt;/h3&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;The object detection was sensitive to the lighting of the room so it had to be readjusted whenever we presented it in a different setting.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;We faced technical limitations from the Raspberry Pi in playing the Processing graphics directly using our Python code, but we were able to overcome this problem by rendering the motion animation as a video.&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;h3 class=&quot;project-body&quot;&gt;For Future Iterations&lt;/h3&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Companion application for mobile&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;The ability to detect multiple objects (e.g. a tray of plate and food)&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Accounting for edge cases (plastic vs. compostable spoon)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;section class=&quot;project-body&quot;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Credit&lt;/h2&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Machine Learning: Jessie Salas&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Ethnographic Interviews: Rachel Lin&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Animations &amp; Frontend: Rachel Lin, Chonyi Lama&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Object Recognition: Lesley Chiang&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Box Construction: Drake Myers&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 06 Dec 2015 13:22:04 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>/trashscan/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/trashscan/</guid>
        
        
        <category>archive</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
